There are 3.7 trillion fish in the ocean. They're looking for one.
Finding Nemo is a animation, family film directed by Andrew Stanton.
Nemo, an adventurous young clownfish, is unexpectedly taken from his
Great Barrier Reef home to a dentist's office aquarium.
It's up to his worrisome father Marlin and a friendly but forgetful fish Dory to bring Nemo home -- meeting
vegetarian sharks, surfer dude turtles, hypnotic jellyfish, hungry seagulls, and more along the way.
Marlin (voice), played by Albert Brooks.
Dory (voice), played by Ellen DeGeneres.
Nemo (voice), played by Alexander Gould.
Gill (voice), played by Willem Dafoe.
Nigel (voice), played by Geoffrey Rush.
Bloat (voice), played by Brad Garrett.
Finding Nemo is a CGI animated film series and Disney media franchise that began with the 2003
film of the same name, produced by Pixar and released by Walt Disney Pictures.
The original film was followed by a standalone
sequel, Finding Dory, released in 2016.
Both films were directed by Andrew Stanton.
The film series received widespread critical acclaim from critics and audiences with two
films released to-date, the series has grossed $1.9 billion worldwide.
The film explores themes of fish, sydney, australia, parent
child relationship, anthropomorphism, harbor.
The tone is intense.